Guide to the Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre Records, 1997-2015 CTC.2009.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Productions, 1997-2014; I.
  - 2010 Season, 14.
    - Hearing Noise in the Silence: A Pinter Celebration, August 2010
      - Video recording - No Man's Land, August 17, 2010; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 18, Folder 6)
        The play No Man's Land was written by Harold Printer and directed by Andrew S. Paul, as part of the Pinter Celebration which ran from July 22 - August 22, 2010 in the Charity Randall and Henry Heymann Theatres. AEA members involved in the production include: Sam Tsoutsouvas, Rick McMillan, Jarrod DiGiorgi, and David Whalen.
      - Video recording - The Dumb Waiter, August 15, 2010; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Video recording - The Hothouse, August 1, 2010; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 18, Folder 8)
        The play The Hothouse was written by Harold Pinter and directed by Matthew Gray as part of the Pinter Celebration, which ran July 22 - Aug 22, 2010. AEA members involved in the production include: Larry John Meyers, Leo Marks, Tami Dixon, Michael Hanrahan, Martin Giles, Doug Pona, Sam Tsoutsouvas, Phill Madore, and Cory F. Goddard.
    - Hobson's Choice, December 2010
      The play Hobson's Choice was written by Harold Brighouse and directed by Andrew S. Paul. It was performed December 2-18, 2010 at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved in the production include Michael Ball, Simon Bradbury, Derdriu Ring, Joseph Domencic, Kathleen Huber, Roger Jerome, John Wascavage, Jon Farris, and Adrienne Wells.
      - Program (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Video recording, December 4, 2010; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 2011 Season, 15.
    - Antony and Cleopatra
      The play Antony and Cleopatra was written by William Shakespeare and directed by James Christy, in a run from May 5-21, 2011, at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Sam Tsoutsouvas, Helena Ruoti, James Sutorius, Leo Marks, James FitzGerald, Daina Michlle Griffith, Jarrod DiGiorgi, Daniel Krell, Ken Bolden, Mark D. Staley, Bria Walker, Shammen McCune, Cory F. Goddard, and Joey Scarillo.
      - Program (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - House & Garden
      House was directed by Andrew S. Paul, and Garden was directed by Melissa Hill Grande. Both plays were written by Alan Ayckbourn. The two plays were performed simultaneously at the Charity Randall and Henry Heymann theatres, July 23 - June 17, 2011. AEA members involved in the production include Nike Doukas, Jon Farris, Michael Fuller, Martin Giles, Tressa Glover, Beth Hylton, David Bryan Jackson, Sarah Manton, Leo Marks, Mary Rawson, Helena Ruoti, Alicia DeMara, and Cory F. Goddard.
      - Program (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Promotional postcard (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Video recording - Garden, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Video recording - House, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - The Importance of Being Earnest
      The Importance of Being Earnest was written by Oscar Wilde and adapted and directed by Conall Morrison, in a run from August 4 -27, 2011 at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Alan Stanford, Leo Marks, David Whalen, Matthew Cleaver, Will Reynolds, James FitzGerald, David Crawford, Martin Giles, and Adrienne Wells.
      - Program (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Race
      The play Race was written by David Mamet, and directed by Andrew S. Paul, in a run from September 8 - October 1, 2011, at the Henry Heymann Theatre. AEA members involved include Alan Bomar Jones, Michael Fuller, John DeMita, and Joanna Obuzor.
      - Program (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Video recording, 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - The Mask of Moriarty
      The Mask of Moriarty was written by Hugh Leonard, and directed by Alan Stanford, in a run from December 1 -17, 2011, at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Jessica Bates, Tony Bingham, James FitzGerald, Martin Giles, Michael Hanrahan, Daryll Heysham, David Whalen, and Adrienne Wells.
      - Program (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 2012 Season, 16.
    - In the Next Room, or The Vibrator Play
      The play In the Next Room or The Vibrator Play was written by Sarah Ruhl, and directed by Alan Stanford in a run from April 19-May 5, 2012, at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include: Jessica Frances Dukes, Brad Heberlee, Melinda Helfrich, Megan McDermott, Philip Winters, and Cory Goddard.
      - Program (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - The Pitmen Painters, June 2012
      The Pitmen Painters was written by Lee Hall, and inspired by the book written by William Feaver. The Pittsburgh premiere production was directed by Andrew S. Paul from May 31 - June 23, 2012 at the Henry Heymann Theatre. AEA members involved include Brad Heberlee, Simon Bradbury, Daryll Heysham, Alan Stanford, Larry John Meyers, Linda Kimbrough, and Cory Goddard.
      - Program (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Video recording, June 3, 2012; 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chekhov Celebration, August 2012
      A Chekhov celebration was a part of PICT's 2012 season. Titled Tragedian In Spite of Himself: A Celebration of the Life and Theatre of Anton Chekhov was performed July 19 - August 26, 2012 at the Charity Randall and Henry Heymann theatres. The plays performed were Three Sisters, directed by Harriet Power, Tom Stoppard's new English version of Ivanov directed by Andrew S. Paul, Brian Friel's The Yalta Game and Afterplay directed by Alan Stanford, and the Chekhov short plays and vaudevilles The Bear, The Proposal, Swan Song, Drama, and On the Evils of Tobacco. AEA members involved in the productions include Christian Conn, Matt DeCaro, Joseph Domencic, Nike Doukas, James FitzGerald, Martin Giles, Cory Goddard, Robert Haley, Leo Marks, Megan McDermott, Allison McLemore, Larry John Meyers, Joanna Obuzor, Helena Ruoti, Alan Stanford, Vera Varlamov, Jonathan Visser, David Whalen, and Terry Wickline.
      - Program (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Video recording - After Chekhov, August 26, 2012; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 4)
        The series After Chekhov is composed of two plays by Brian Friel, Afterplay and The Yalta Game, both directed by Alan Stanford during the Chekhov Celebration. AEA members in Afterplay include Martin Giles and Helena Ruoti, and AEA members in The Yalta Game include Allison McLemore and Jonathan Visser. The stage manager for both productions, Cory Goddard, is also an AEA member.
      - Video recording - Funny Chekhov, August 25, 2012; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 5)
        The series Funny Chekhov contains five plays and vaudevilles by Chekhov; they are The Proposal: A Vaudeville directed by Nike Doukas, The Bear: A Vaudeville directed by Martin Giles, On the Evils of Tobacco: A Comic Sketch directed by Andrew S. Paul, Drama: A Comedy directed by Larry John Meyers, and Swang Song: A One-Act Play directed by Leo Marks. AEA members involved in these five productions include: Christian Conn, Matt DeCaro, Nike Doukas, James FitzGerald, Leo Marks, Larry John Meyers, Joseph Domencic, Robert Haley, Terry Wickline, Alan Stanford, and Joanna Obuzor.
      - Video recording - Ivanov, August 25, 2012; 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 6)
        The play Ivanov was written by Anton Chekhov and adapted by Tom Stoppard. It was directed by Andrew Paul as part of the Chekhov Celebration from July 19 - August 26, 2012, in the Charity Randall and Henry Heymann Theatres. AEA members involved include: David Whalen, Nike Doukas, Alan Stanford, Matt DeCaro, Leo Marks, James FitzGerald, Martin Giles, Helena Ruoti, Megan McDermott, Jonathan Visser, Terry Wickline, Robert Haley, Joe Domencic, and Joanna Obuzor.
      - Video recording - Three Sisters, August 26, 2012; 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 7)
        The play Three Sisters was written by Anton Chekhov, and translated by Paul Schmidt. It was directed by Harriet Power in a run that was part of the Chekhov Celebration, which ran July 19-August 26, 2012, at the Charity Randall and Henry Heymann Theatres. AEA members involved include: Christian Conn, Nike Doukas, Allison McLemore, Vera Varlamov, Megan McDermott, Joseph Domencic, David Whalen, Leo Marks, Jonathan Visser, Larry John Meyers, Robert Haley, and Cory Goddard.
    - The School for Lies
      The School for Lies was written by David Ives and is a free adaptation of Moliere's The Misanthrope. It was directed by Andrew S. Paul in a run from November 29 - December 15, 2012, at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Leo Marks, Nike Doukas, Robin Abramson, Joel Ripka, Helena Ruoti, James FitzGerald, Martin Giles, Ben Blazer, Matt DeCaro, and Cory Goddard.
      - Program (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 2013 Season, 17.
    - Our Class
      The play Our Class was written by Tadeusz Slobodzianek in a version by Ryan Craig and was directed by Aoife Spillane-Hinks, in a run from April 10 - May 4, 2013, at the Henry Heymann Theatre. AEA members involved include Caroline Shannon, Bernard Balbot, Aaron White, Jonathan Visser, Justin Fortunato, Quinn Partrick Shannon, Rafael Goldstein, Caitlin Roper, and Cory Goddard.
      - Program (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Video recording, 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - The Kreutzer Sonata
      The Kreutzer Sonata was written by Nancy Harris and based on a novella by Leo Tolstoy. It was directed by Alan Stanford in a run from May 30 - June 22, 2013, at the Henry Heymann Theatre. AEA members involved include Martin Giles and Cory F. Goddard.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Video recording, 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Lady Windermere's Fan
      The play Lady Windermere's Fan was written by Oscar Wilde and adapted and directed by Alan Stanford. It ran from July 11-27, 2013, at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Jodi Gage, Leo Marks, John DeMita, Nike Doukas, Helena Ruoti, Martin Giles, James FitzGerald, Lisa Ann Goldsmith, David Whalen, Cory Goddard, and Joanna Obuzor.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Video recording, 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Don Juan Comes Back From the War
      The play Don Juan Comes Back from the War was written by Odon von Horvath, and a new version was written by Duncan Macmillan. The production was directed by Alan Stanford in a run from August 8-31, 2013 at the Henry Heymann Theatre. AEA members involved include David Whalen, Nike Doukas, Melinda Helfrich, Karen Baum, Catherine Moore, and Cory Goddard.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Video recording, Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - A Skull in Connemara
      The play A Skull in Connemara was written by Martin McDonagh and directed by Martin Giles, in a run from September 12-28 in the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include: James Keegan, Jason McCune, Sharon Brady, Alec Silberblatt, and Cory F. Goddard.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Video recording, 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - The Crucifer of Blood
      The Crucifer of Blood was written by Paul Giovanni and directed by Matt Torney. The play ran from December 4-21, 2013 at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include David Whalen, Justin R. G. Holcomb, Daryll Heysham, Ken Bolden, Jonathan Visser, Malcolm Madera, Michael Fuller, Cory F. Goddard, and Caitlin Roper.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 2014 Season, 18.
    - Blithe Spirit, May 10, 2014
      The play Blithe Spirit was written by Noël Coward and directed by Alan Stanford. It was performed May 1-17, 2014 at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved in the production include Karen Baum, Jim FitzGerald, Daina Michelle Griffith, Mary Rawson, Dan Rodden, and Cory F. Goddard.
      - Video recording, May 10, 2014; 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Waiting for Godot, June 15, 2014
      The play Waiting for Godot was written by Samuel Beckett and directed by Aoife Spillane-Hinks during June 5-21, 2014 at the Charity Randall Theatre. AEA members involved include Ken Bolden, James FitzGerald, Martin Giles, Alan Stanford, and Cory F. Goddard.
      - Program (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Video recording, June 15, 2014; 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Woman and Scarecrow
      - Video recording, 1 video Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Observe the Sons of Ulster Marching Towards the Somme, September 14, 2014
      - Video recording, September 14, 2014; 2 videos Digital video cassette (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Organizational and Marketing Files, 1997-2008; II.
  This series contains a small collection of files relating to the organizational history of the Pittsburgh Irish & Classical Theatre. The are some early documents relating to the creation of the organization, board member materials, and materials relating to their fundraising events.
  - Bylaws, January 1997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Education Initiative flyer for the 2006 season (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Executive summary and business plans, 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Gala and Fundraiser Invitations, 2000-2008 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    The invitation for the 2005 PICT Fall Gala is a 16 minute DVD with scenes from many of their productions.
  - Event programs, 2000-2001 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 2000-2008 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1997-2000, 2001-2007 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Organizational materials and board member correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box 22, Folder 8-12)
  - Proclamations from the City of Pittsburgh, 1997-2008 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Season brochures, 1998-2008 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Posters, 1998-2015; III.
  The posters have been given their own series within this collection. Due to their size, they could not be filed with the other materials from their production. In general, the posters all measure 25" x 10". There is a poster for nearly every production in PICT's history through 2015.
  - 1998 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 1)
    - Season poster, 1.
    - Translations, 2.
    - Too Clever By Half, 3.
    - The White Devil, 4.
  - 1999 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 2)
    - Juno and the Paycock, 1.
    - The Rivals, 2.
    - Racing Demon, 3.
  - 2000 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 3)
    - Faith Healer, 1.
    - Faith Healer - Pittsburgh Presents version, 2.
    - The Cripple of Inishman, 3.
    - Henceforward, 4.
    - The Picture of Dorian Gray, 5.
  - 2001 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 4)
    - Tartuffe, 1.
    - Tonight at 8:30, 2.
    - The Seagull, 3.
  - 2002 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 5)
    - The Gigli Concert
    - She Stoops to Conquer, 1.
    - Aristocrats, 2.
    - Faith Healer - Ireland Tour, 3.
  - 2003 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 6)
    - Major Barbara, 1.
    - Copenhagen, 2.
  - 2004 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 7)
    - A Woman of No Importance, 1.
    - Travesties, 2.
    - Stones in His Pockets, 3.
    - Uncle Vanya, 4.
    - Fall Gala - One Wilde Night, September 27, 2004; 5.
    - The Dead, 6.
  - 2005 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 8)
    - Henry IV, 1.
    - Chaplin, 2.
    - Heartbreak House, 3.
    - Stones in His Pocket, 4.
    - The False Servant, 5.
    - Henry, 6.
  - 2006 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 9)
    - The Pillowman, 1.
    - School for Scandal, 2.
    - Boston Marriage, 3.
    - Endgame / BeckettFest: Happy Days, 5.
    - The Shaughraun, 6.
  - 2007 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 10)
    - Julius Caesar, 1.
    - Stuff Happens, 2.
    - Hedda Gabler, 3.
    - The Lieutenant of Inishmore, 4.
    - Private Lives, 5.
    - Pride and Prejudice, 6.
  - 2008 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 11)
    - King Lear, 1.
    - An Ideal Husband, 2.
    - Wilde Tales, 3.
    - Salome, 4.
    - Playboy of the Western World / Synge Cycle, 6.
    - Dublin Carol /St. Nicholas, 7.
  - 2009 Season (Map-case 2, Oversize 12)
    - Rock & Roll, 1.
    - What the Butler Saw, 2.
    - Doubt, 3.
  - 2010 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 13)
    - Beautiful Dreamers, 1.
    - Othello, 2.
    - Hobson's Choice, 3.
    - Pinter Celebration, 4.
  - 2011 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 14)
    - Antony and Cleopatra, 1.
    - House & Garden, 2.
    - The Importance of Being Earnest, 3.
    - Race - Autographed by cast, 4.
    - The Mask of Moriarty, 4.
  - 2012 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 15)
    - In the Next Room, or the Vibrator Play, 1.
    - The Pitmen Painters, 2.
    - Chekhov Celebration, 3.
    - The School for Lies - Autographed by cast, 4.
  - 2013 Season (Map-case 2-5, Drawer 16)
    - Our Class - Autographed by cast, 1.
    - The Kreutzer Sonata, 2.
    - Lady Windermere's Fan, 3.
    - Don Juan Comes Back From the War, 4.
    - A Skull in Connemara, 5.
    - The Crucifer of Blood, 6.
  - 2014 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 17)
    - Blithe Spirit, 1.
    - Waiting for Godot, 2.
    - Woman and Scarecrow - Autographed by cast, 3.
    - Observe the Sons of Ulster Marching Towards the Somme, 4.
    - Macbeth, 5.
    - Great Expectations, 6.
  - 2015 Season (Map-case 2-5, Oversize 18)
    - For the Tree to Drop, 1.
    - Jacques Brel is Alive and Well and Living in Paris, 2.
    - How the Other Half Loves, 3.
    - Sharon's Grave, 4.
    - The Tempest, 5.